

Thanh Hai Chau

Electrical & Electronics Engineer

🚨 Profile

Underwater Robotics, Electronic Design Engineer, with over 1 year of experience PCB Designer / Board Architecture (stack up) / Schematic Capture / Assembly and Fabrication Drawings. Accomplishing custom printed circuit board design for many research projects especially for autonomous underwater vehicles. Being a young engineer with enthusiastic and passion, I can work in highvolume workflow, with creative problem resolution capabilities. Seeking a position where my experience, capabilities and passion will enable me to contribute to a company's objective.

Work Experience

Electronics Engineer at Ho Chi Minh University of Technology, **Ho Chi Minh City**

NOVEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

- Schematic capture and printed circuit board layout using Altium.
- Responsible of creating printed circuit board footprints / land patterns using Altium. Designed of multi-layer PCB.
- Experienced in power distribution network (PDN) issues such as ground bounce, rail collapse, cross-talk, and EMI issues.
- Understand in signal integrity problems in high-speed PCB.
- Addressed/resolved signal noises in multi-layer PCB.
- Designed of H-Bridge for 600 Brush-less DC Motor.
- Designed of Electrical Systems for Underwater Robots.
- Brought forth a hard-work ethic and self-motivated attitude.

Vice Leader at Bach Khoa Robotics and Automation Club, Ho Chi Minh City

AUGUST 2019 - JANUARY 2021

- Organized a Humanoid Robot Contest 2019.
- Organized a Conference about Science, Technology, Robotics & Automation 2019.
- Electronic introductory training for first-year students.
- Assisted with the recruiting and interviewing of new members.

Education

Bachelor, Ho Chi Minh University of Technology, Ho Chi Minh City

NOVEMBER 2014 - JUNE 2018

- · Control Engineering and Automation.
- · Graduate with good rank.
- · Graduated thesis: "Study And Build An Underwater Robot".

Contact

29/03/1996

A Male

🏠 13/9 Tran Van Hoang Street, 9 Ward, Tan Binh District, Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

+84383191679

thanhhaipif96@gmail.com

Links

www.facebook.com/thanhhai

bker96/

github.com/thanhhaibk96

www.behance.net/thanhhichu

www.linkedin.com/in/than h-hai-chau-816119131/

Skills

Software Used: Altium, Solidwork

Microsoft Office

Teamwork

Communication

Leadership

Creative Thinking

Time Management

Languages

English

Hobbies

Reading Books, Sports (Gym, Soccer), Listening to Music, Traveling.

Master, Ho Chi Minh University of Technology, Ho Chi Minh City

NOVEMBER 2018 - NOVEMBER 2021

- Control Engineering and Automation
- Graduate with good rank
- Graduated thesis: "Implementation Of Sliding-Mode Controller For Underwater Vehicle In Horizontal Plane"

Extra-Currilar Activities

Member at Project - C of Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City: "Study And Build 600W Thruster For Underwater Robot", Ho Chi Minh City

OCTOBER 2017 - APRIL 2018

- Designed of H-Bridge for 600 Brush-less DC Motor.
- Programming C for STM32F1 Micro-controller.
- Designed of Graphics User Interface using C#.

Leader of An Electronic Team at Project - B of Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City: "Study And Build Autonomous Underwater Vehicle For Military Applications", Ho Chi Minh Citv

NOVEMBER 2018 - OCTOBER 2021

- Managed and assign work to the electronic team.
- Designed of electrical boards for robot.
- Programming C/C++/C#/ROS.
- Experienced in using embedded PC such as: Raspberry, Jetson Nano and STM32F4 Micro-controller.
- Experienced in Embedded Linux.

Courses

Signal and Power Integrity Simulation, HiTech Education

APRIL 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

References

Dr. Ngoc Huy Tran from Ho Chi Minh University of Technology



